-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
福尔摩斯探案 之归来记
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第四季 第三集
银额马
事情不妙
It's no good.
我必须要去一趟
I shall have to go.
去一趟 去哪?
Go?
Go where?
King's Pyland
King's Pyland.
昨天晚上Devonshire警局的Gregory督察
Last evening Inspector Gregory
逮捕了知名的赛马人
of the Devonshire Constabulary
Fitzroy Simpson
arrested well known racing personality
并且控诉他谋杀了驯马师John Straker
Fitzroy Simpson
and charged him with the murder
of trainer, John Straker.
哦 请进
Oh, come in.
又有两封电报 福尔摩斯先生
Two more telegrams, Mr. Holmes.
谢谢你 Hudson女士
Thank you, Mrs. Hudson.
你这两天一直在不停地问它们
You've been bombarded with these
又是Gregory督察发来的
the last couple of days.
Another one from Inspector Gregory.
和一封Ross上校的
A note from Colonel Ross.
哇 那是马的主人
Awe, that's the horse's owner.
谢谢你 亲爱的
Thank you my dear.
华生
Watson,
我犯了一个大错
I had made a blunder,
是那些只读了你的传记而知道我的人
which I am afraid is a more common occurrence
than anyone would think
不会想到的一件常事
who only knew me through your memoirs.
不过事实是我不敢相信
But the fact is that I could not believe
像银额马这样一匹一眼就能认出的马
that so a remarkable a horse as Silver Blaze
会就这么消失...
could disappear,
特别是在像Dartmoor这样的僻静之地
especially in the seclusion of
somewhere like Dartmoor.
我无时无刻都希望可以听到消息
From hour to hour I expect to hear
那个拐马者就是杀害John Straker的凶手
that the abductor was the murderer of John Straker
而且马也找回来了
and the horse had been found
但是看上去不是这么回事
but that doesn't seem to be the case.
我会很乐意跟你一起去
I should be happy to go with you.
不 在Tavistock呢
No, Tavistock.
如果我不妨碍你的话
If I should not be in the way.
哦 我亲爱的华生
Oh my dear Watson,
你愿意同去是对我很大的支持
you would confer a great favor upon me by coming.
我相信不会浪费你的时间
I'm sure your time will not be misspent.
我保证这绝对是件独一无二的案子
The case promises to be absolutely unique.
我们正好能赶上去Paddington的火车
We can just catch our train from Paddington.
哦 华生 你可以带上你的双筒望远镜吗
Oh Watson, would you be so kind
as to bring your field glasses?
Hudson女士 我们要去Dartmoor
Mrs. Hudson, were off to Dartmoor.
请出示车票
Tickets please.
谢谢你 巡票员
Thank you, Inspector.
谢谢
Thank you.
华生 我们今天的速度不错
Watson, were going well.
现在的速度是...
Our speed at present
每小时五十三英里半
is fifty-three and half miles an hour.
我没留心去数每隔四分之一英里的路杆
I've not observed the quarter mile post.
我也没有
Nor have, I
但是这条铁路边的电线杆的间隔
but the telegraphed posts
...是六十码
on this line are sixty yards apart.
这是很简单的计算
The calculation is a simple one.
那份受人瞩目 喜欢过度渲染的体育报纸
Has that remarkably, colored, sporting paper
提到了任何关于我们的马的事吗
anything to say on the subject of our horse?
什么?
What?
哦 有的
Oh, Yes.
好
Yes.
在这里
Here we are.
银额马
Silver Blaze.
银额马拥有Isonomy的血统
Silver Blaze is from Isonomy stock.
Isonomy
Isonomy.
而且像它著名的祖先一样 保持着辉煌的记录
And holds as brilliant a record
as his famous ancestor.
它现在五岁了
He's now in his fifth year
每次都能在赛马场上
and has brought in turn
each of the prize of the turf
为他幸运的主人Ross上校赢得奖金
to Colonel Ross his fortunate owner.
眼下灾难发生之际
At the time of the catastrophe
它是Wessex杯中最有望夺冠的一匹
he was first favored for the Wessex Cup.
赔率是二比一
The odds quoted being two to one against.
作为赛马嗜好者一向最爱的宠驹
He's always been a prime favorite
从来没有让他们失望过
of the racing public
and has never yet disappointed them.
尽管赌注悬殊
In spite of the unfavorable prize,
还是有巨款押在了它身上
a great deal of money has been placed upon him,
所以很明显
so it is obvious, therefore,
许多人出于自身利益的考量
that there are many people
with the strongest interest
会想方设法阻止银额马出赛
in preventing Silver Blaze
from being there at the fall of the flag.
好吧 Baynes
All right, Baynes,
请在这里停一下 这里的风景不错
will you stop here please
cause this is a rather good view.
那边就是King's Pyland 福尔摩斯先生
Now that's King's Pyland, over there Mr. Holmes.
我的驯马厩 马就在那里失踪的
You know my training stable
这的布局是什么样的 Ross上校?
where the missing horse was kept.
What exactly does your establishment consist of,
Colonel Ross?
那处是驯马师的房子
Well, there's the trainer's house,
可怜的Straker和他的老婆住在一起
where poor Straker lived with his wife
还有一个女仆
and a maidservant.
他跟在你身边多久了 先生
How long had he been with you sir?
哦 当了我五年的骑师
Oh, five years at jockey
直到他发福无法再上马
until he got too heavy for the weighing chair.
接下来七年做了我的驯马师
Then seven years as my trainer.
是的 他水平一流
Yes, he was a first class man.
我猜更远处就是马厩
And I presume the stables are beyond?
是的 马场不大但是很不错
Yes, yes not a big yard, it's a good one.
我注重的是质量不是数量
My thought is quality not quantity.
在赛马场上活跃的人都可以告诉你这点 福尔摩斯先生
As anyone connected with the turf
谢谢 督察
will tell you, Mr. Holmes.
你看 现在
Yes, thank you, Inspector.
You see, at the moment,
马场里只养了五匹马
I'm merely five horses in the yard.
我知道你让其中两匹参加了Wessex杯 Ross上校
I see you have two of them
entered for the Wessex Cup, Colonel Ross.
没错 是的
That's right, yes.
银额马和Bayard
Yes, Silver Blaze and Bayard.
可别说出去 派上Bayard是为了去领跑
But between us Bayard is intended for a pacemaker.
训练这么名贵的动物
Well with such valuable animals under his charge,
我想你的驯马师Straker先生
I imagine your trainer Mr. Straker
一定采取了一些预防措施
must have taken some precautions.
哦 没有错
Oh yes indeed.
有三个小马倌和马匹一起生活
Three stable lads lived with the horses
天黑之后其中一个会在马厩值班
and after dark one of the lads
其他两个会睡在阁楼里
was always on duty in the stables
while the other two sleep above in loft.
那边是不是还有一个驯马场?
Is that another training stable over there?
是的 那里是Mapleton
Yes, that's Mapleton.
Backwater勋爵的马场
Lord Backwater's yard.
Backwater勋爵有匹Desberly
Lord Backwater?
是Wessex杯的二号种子吧
Lord Backwater owns Desberly,
是匹不错的马
second favorite for the Wessex Cup.
但和银额马不是一个等级的
This is not a bad horse.
Not in the same class as Silver Blaze.
那个人叫Silas Brown
Fellow called, Silas Brown,
是Backwater的驯马师 谜一样的人
trains for Backwater, [unintelligible] himself.
连Straker也搞不懂他
Nor could Straker come to that.
我想是竞争对手的缘故吧
There's a natural rivalry I presume.
不止如此
Rather more than that.
我们可以继续走了吗?
Shall we drive on?
好的
Yes, indeed.
走了 Baynes
All right, Baynes.
Gregory督察
Inspector Gregory,
对马匹去向的调查有没有进展?
are there any further developments
as to the where abouts of the horse?
完全没有
Nothing at all.
我们在这个方面几乎停滞不前
We have made very little progress
in that direction.
我不能想象像这样一匹银额马
I can't imagine how a horse like Silver Blaze
会在这样的地方失踪
could go missing for so long in a place like this.
我也想不到
Nor can I.
我必须告诉你 福尔摩斯先生
I must tell you Mr. Holmes,
我一开始并不完全接受 Gregory督察的建议
that at first I was not at all taken
with Inspector Gregory's suggestion
把你请到这里来
that you should be asked to come down here.
我不喜欢业余的 明白吗?
I don't like amateurs you see?
Ha!
但是你还是给我发了电报 上校
But you did send me a telegram, Colonel.
看来没有别人可以找到我的马了
Well no one else seems to be able to find my horse.
如果你问我会是谁 我会说是那些
If you ask me it's these damn gypsies
散居在荒野上的该死的吉普赛浪人
wondering all over the moor.
早晚会出丑事 我说这话很多年了
It's a perfect scandal, I've said so for years.
我的人在过去的两天中
My men have seen
调查了在Dartmoor的每个吉普赛人 上校
every group of gypsies on Dartmoor
in the last two days, Colonel.
而且搜查了南Devon的每个马厩 采石场和洞穴
And searched every stable yard,
quarry and cave in south Devon.
这绝对是一个迷
It's an absolute mystery.
我期待你能创造奇迹 福尔摩斯先生
I expect a miracle from you, Mr. Holmes.
Gregory督察
Inspector Gregory,
我在苏格兰场的朋友跟我说
my friends at Scotland Yard tell me
你在英国侦探圈中 迅速地建立了自己的声誉
that you're rapidly making a reputation for yourself
in the English detective service.
我也是个热心学习您办案方法的学生 福尔摩斯先生
I'm a keen student of your methods too,
我有两个主要证人在等您
Mr. Holmes.
I have the two principle, witnesses waiting for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
在这里 福尔摩斯先生
In here, Mr. Holmes.
他们是谁?
Who are they?
女仆Edith Baxter
Edith Baxter, the maid
以及在星期一晚上值班的马童Hunter
and Hunter, the stable boy
who was on duty on Monday night.
那是九点刚过几分 先生
It was just a few minutes after nine o'clock, sir.
我端着Hunter先生的晚餐
I was carrying Mr. Hunter supper
要送到从对面的屋子去
across from the house.
但是 Baxter小姐
Awe, but Miss Baxter,
晚餐吃的是什么呢
what did the supper consist of?
是一盘咖喱羊肉 先生
It was a dish of curried mutton, sir.
突然我听见了一个男人的声音
Suddenly I heard a man's voice.
我可以告诉你 先生 我完全没有心理准备
Did not give me a turn, I can tell you sir.
不好意思 小姐
Excuse me, Miss.
你想干什么 先生
What do you want, sir?
你能告诉我这是哪里吗
Can you tell me where I am?
就在我几乎决定露宿荒野的时候
I'd almost made up my mind to sleep on the moor
看见了这里的灯光
when I saw the light.
这里是King's Pyland驯马场 先生
This is King's Pyland training stable, sir.
那真是太走运了
What a stroke of luck.
我知道会有小马倌
I understand there's stable lad
晚上睡在里面
who sleeps here at night.
毫无疑问你端的是他的晚餐了
No doubt that's his supper you have there.
我相信你不会那么骄傲
I'm sure you wouldn't be too proud to earn
连一条新裙子的钱也不屑赚吧
yourself the price of a new dress would you?
看 今晚把这个给那男孩
See the boy has this tonight
你就能得到可以买一条最漂亮的连衣裙的钱
and you shall have the prettiest frock
我不能要
money can buy.
I couldn't!
Ned!
外面有一个男人拦住了我
There's a man stopped me out there.
我很害怕
I'm ever so frightened.
他想干什么
What did he want?
他问起了你
He asked after you.
让我给你一些东西
He asked me to give you something.
是什么
What was it?
我不知道
I don't know.
是一样白色的东西
It was white.
他现在在哪
Where is he now?
他走了
He's gone.
你最好马上回屋去
We best cut back to the house quick.
告诉老爷
Tell the governor!
好的 Ned
Yes Ned.
晚上好
Good evening.
我想和你说几句话
I want a word with you.
你来这里有什么事
What business have you here?
是件能让你的口袋鼓起来的买卖 小伙子
It's a business that may
put something in your pocket, my lad.
你现在有两匹参加Wessex杯的马
Now you've two horses entering the Wessex Cup,
银额马和Bayard
Silver Blaze and Bayard,
给我透点内幕
let me have the straight tip
不会对你有坏处
and you won't be the loser.
Bayard真的可以在五弗隆的距离里 (约200米)
Is it the fact that at the weights Bayard
超过银额马一百码吗 所以大家...?
can give the other a hundred yards
你别想从我这里得到任何消息 滚!
and five furlongs in the...
You wont get any tips around here, get out!
追上他 追上他
After him boy, after him!
老爷和其他人已经来得很及时了
The governor and the others
came down soon enough.
但我们没有找到那个男人的半点踪迹
We found not a sight or sound of the man.
等一下
One moment.
你把狗放出去之后
When you let the dog out
门有没有关上?
did you leave the door open behind you?
问得好 华生 问得好
Oh excellent, Watson, excellent.
这正是我要问的
It's just the point I was going to make.
我把门锁上了 先生
I locked the door behind me sir.
-我发誓 -好孩子
I swear it.
Good lad.
Fitzroy Simpson认罪了吗?
Does Fitzroy Simpson admit to all this?
他对此全盘否认
He denies nothing.
他说来这是为了买消息
He says he came for information.
那张白条是什么?
What about the white paper?
他说那是一张五镑纸币
He says it was a five-pound note.
接下来发生了什么
What happened next?
先生
Well sir,
那是天刚亮的时候
it was about dawn
女主人走进我的卧室
when the mistress came into my bedroom
叫我跟她走
and told me to come with her.
当她醒来时发现Straker先生的床是空的
Well when she woke
she'd found Mr. Straker's bed empty.
天啊
Heavens!
马不见了
The horse is gone...
还有马勒 (安放在马头周围 用来牵引的马具)
and the bridle.
Ned 醒醒
Ned, wake up!
把他叫醒
Wake the boys.
Ned
Ned!
醒醒! 醒醒Ned!
Wake up.
Wake up, Ned!
Bill! Robbie! 快来!
Bill, Robbie come quick,
银额马不见了
Silver Blaze is gone.
这边
Over here.
他死了 先生
He was dead sir.
他的头...
His head
被打得陷进去了一块
it was all knocked in.
实在是太可怕了
It was terrible.
头部受到了某种钝器的重击
It was a terrible blow on the head
这就是他的死因
from some blunt instrument
that had killed him.
很明显他曾拼命抵抗过
It was clear that he had
defended himself most vigorously.
一把血迹斑斑的小刀
The blood stained knife.
和大腿上伤口 你们说呢
As to the wound on the thigh, who can tell?
腿上的伤口可能是 Straker摔倒的时候造成的
Well it is possible that the wound on the thigh
could have been caused as Straker fell.
那个男孩被下药了
The lad here was drugged.
在他的咖喱中有一定分量的麻醉药
Appreciable quantities of powered opium
were found in his carry.
所有人吃得都是一样的吗
Did all the household eat the same dish?
是的 先生
Yes sir.
我亲自下厨再端上餐桌
I made it myself and served it.
这条黑红色的围巾
This black and red scarf?
那位先生跟我说话时就是戴着这条围巾
The gentleman was wearing that scarf
我可以在圣经面前发誓 先生
when he talked to me.
I'd swear that on the Bible, sir.
谢谢你 华生
Thank you Watson.
谢谢
Thank you.
别这样 别这样!
Stop it boy.
来吧 乖狗狗
Stop it.
乖狗狗
Come on.
Good dog.
Good boy.
我的理论是
My theory is that Simpson
Simpson是想方设法收买情报
was under some strong obligation to Nobble
或者用别的法子让马无法上场
or otherwise incapacitate this horse
不能参加Wessex杯
so that he would be unable to run in the Wessex Cup.
在男孩的饭里下麻醉药倒是挺聪明
Clever move that, putting opium in the boy's food
利用那窗户很容易得手
and easy enough through that window.
是的 下面就简单了
Yes.
Then it was simple.
他用一把复制好的钥匙
He obtained a duplicate key,
把马牵了出去
led out the horse,
但他运气不好
it was his bad luck
Straker很警觉 追踪他到了野外
that Straker was alert enough
to catch him up on the moor,
在对抗中 马逃走了
in the struggle the horse bolted.
没有证据说明
That's no proof
Simpson杀了Straker
that Simpson killed Straker.
我们有足够对他不利的证据
Well the evidence against him is very strong.
毫无疑问他来这有不可告人的目的
He was undoubtedly here on some devious business.
他给马倌下了毒
He poisoned the stable lad.
他手上有一根很沉的铅头手杖
He had in his hand a heavy stick
weighted with lead
而且在死者的手上有他的围巾
and his scarf was found
in the dead man's hand.
当我用这些和他对质时 他面如死灰
And he went pale as death
我真的认为在陪审团面前 证据是游刃有余了
when I confronted him with that fact.
I really think we have enough
不 不
to go before a jury.
不
No, no.
督察
No.
一个聪明点的律师完全可以把它们驳倒
Inspector?
A cleaver council would tear it all to rags.
-在他身上发现了复制钥匙吗 -没有
Has a duplicate key been found in his possession?
是哪个药剂师把麻醉药卖给他的?
No.
Well what chemist sold him the powered opium?
更重要的是
And above all how could he,
一个陌生人是怎么在这里把一匹马藏起来了
a stranger in this district,
更何况是一匹这样的银额马
hide a horse and such a horse as Silver Blaze?
我同意证据都是间接的
I agree the evidence is circumstantial
但我认为布在 Fitzroy Simpson周围的网很紧密
but I think the net is drawn pretty tightly
我相信他已经是网中鱼
around Fitzroy Simpson
and I believe he is our man.
他是一个怎样的人? 为什么会做出这种事呢?
What sort of fellow is he
and why would he do such a thing?
Fitzroy Simpson出身于名门望族
Fitzroy Simpson is a man of
excellent birth and dedication.
很不幸地他在赛马场上 输掉了一大笔财富
Unfortunately he has
squandered a fortune on the turf,
导致他负债累累
which has put him in the hands of moneylenders
并且成为一个不择手段的赌马人
and unscrupulous bookmakers.
在赛马场上确实有这样的人
Plenty of those sharks in the racing world.
我不知道你也会赌 华生
I didn't know that
什么? 我只是...
you were a betting man, Watson.
What?
偶尔在赛马上下笔小赌注
Oh, just the occasional flutter.
我猜你们有了份Straker死时
I presume an inventory has been made
他口袋里物件的清单
of what Straker had in his pockets
如果你想看的话 东西就在我的客厅里
at the time of his death?
I have the things themselves
in the sitting room
if you would care to see them.
伦敦Weiss公司
Weiss & Co., London.
从血迹来看 我猜这就是死者抓着的刀
From the bloodstains, I presume,
this is the knife that was found
没错
in the dead man's grasp.
这更接近你的专业 医生
Yes indeed.
This is more in your line, Doctor.
是我们所称的为眼翳刀 (用于割除角膜组织的翳状赘肉)
This is what we call a cataract knife.
非常锋利的刀刃
Very delicate blade
专门用于非常精密的手术
devised for very delicate work.
会有人如此随身携带可真稀奇 福尔摩斯
Strange thing for a man to take
on so rough an expedition, Holmes,
怎么会没有戳破他的口袋呢
especially as it wouldn't shut in his pocket.
在尸体旁 我们找到了小刀的软木圆鞘
Awe, the tip was guarded by a disc of cork,
which we found beside the body.
你很出色 督察
You impress me, Inspector.
谢谢
Thank you.
Straker夫人说原来它是放在梳妆台上
Mrs. Straker says it was on the dressing table.
这可能是他当时最随手可得的东西了
It was probably
我明白了
the nearest thing to him at the time.
I see.
马料商的账单
Corn merchants bill.
Colonel Ross上校的指示信
Instructions from Colonel Ross.
这个又是什么?
Awe what have we here?
一张女衣店账单
A milliner's account
三十七镑十五先令
for thirty-seven pounds fifteen shillings
伦敦邦德街Lesurier夫人开具
for a Madame Lesurier,
of Bond Street, London,
给William Derbyshire先生
to a Mr. William Derbyshire.
Straker女士告诉我们 Derbyshire是他丈夫的一个朋友
Mrs. Straker tells us
that Derbyshire was a friend of her husband's
偶尔他的信会寄到这里
and on occasionally
had his letters addressed here.
二十二基尼(金币 值21先令)
Twenty-two guineas.
对一件衣服来说贵了点
Somewhat heavy for a single costume.
Derbyshire夫人喜欢贵的东西
Mrs. Derbyshire had rather expensive taste.
是的
Yes.
看来没有其他有用的东西了 督察
Well there appears to be
nothing more to learn here, Inspector,
我们去犯罪现场吧
shall we move onto the scene of the crime?
好的 当然
Yes, of course.
你先 华生
After you Watson.
你抓住他们了吗 督察
Have you got them, Inspector?
有什么新消息吗
Is there any more news?
恐怕没有 Straker夫人
I'm afraid not, Mrs. Straker.
但是福尔摩斯先生和华生医生
But Mr. Holmes and Doctor Watson
从伦敦赶来协助我们
have come down from London to help us.
我跟你保证 我们会全力以赴
I assure you we're doing everything possible.
祝你好运 福尔摩斯先生
I wish you good luck, Mr. Holmes.
谢谢你 夫人 我对你的损失深表遗憾
Oh thank you madam and my commiserations
on your great loss.
我们肯定见过面吧?
Surely we've met?
之前在Plymouth的游园会上
At a garden party
in Plymouth some time ago.
没有 先生
No sir.
你弄错了
You are mistaken.
不 我可是非常肯定的
No, do you know I could have sworn it.
你穿着一件浅灰色丝绸衣服
You wore a costume of dove-colored silk
上面有鸵鸟毛做的装饰物
with ostrich feather trimming.
我从来没有这样的衣服 先生
I never had such a dress, sir.
那就清楚了 谢谢你
That quite settles it.
Thank you.
这就是挂着外套的灌木
That is the bush where the coat was hanging.
那天天气怎么样
What was the weather like?
没什么风 雨挺大
Wind calm bit of rain about.
那外套不是被风吹到灌木上 而是人挂的
And the coat was not blown against the bush
哦 是的 是被人放的
but placed there?
督察
Oh yes, it was placed.
不 不 不好
Inspector!
No, no, no!
这片土地被太多人踏过
So many people have trampled around this land.
一定有很多人到过
There have been many people here.
那张垫子是故意摆在那里 供大家落脚的
That piece of matting has been placed there
and we have all stood upon there.
可老百姓不是
Not the general public.
我这个袋子里面有...
I have in this bag
John Straker穿的一只靴子
one of the boots John Straker wore,
一只Fitzroy Simpson的鞋子
one of Fitzroy Simpson's shoes,
一块银额马的马蹄铁
and a cast horseshoe of Silver Blaze.
谢谢你 督察
Thank you, Inspector.
燃了一半的蜡烛
Half burned wax candle.
不敢相信我居然忽视了它们
I cannot understand how I came to overlook them.
它们被埋在土里 自然看不见了
Oh they're invisible, buried in the mud.
我能看见是因为我找的就是它们
I only saw them because I was looking for them.
什么 你早料到能发现它们?
What, you expected to find them?
我认为这并不是不可能的
I thought it not unlikely.
恐怕这里没有其他线索了
I'm afraid there are no more tracks.
周围一百码之内都检查过了
I've examined the ground
for a hundred yards in every direction.
真是个愉快的夜晚啊
What a pleasant evening.
我想我要去散个步了 伸伸腿
I think I'll take a walk, stretch my legs.
-华生 -没错
Watson?
这个我带走了 为了好运
Yes, indeed.
屋里还有事等着我做
I'll take this for luck.
之后Ross上校会来接我们回Tavistock
I have some work to do in the house,
then Colonel Ross is coming
to take us back to Tavistock.
晚安 警官
Good evening, Constable.
假设银额马挣脱了缰绳
Suppose that Silver Blaze broke away,
那它会跑到哪里去呢
where would he have gone?
如果它还在旷野上晃悠
If he'd run loose on the moor
到现在肯定会被人看到了
he'd have surely been seen by now.
可能那个吉普赛人的理论是正确的
Perhaps the gypsy theory's correct.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
马是非常喜欢群居的生物
A horse is a most gregarious creature.
既然它没有回到King's Pyland自己的马厩
Now he did not go back to King's Pyland
那就一定是去了...Mapleton
to his own stable,
so he must have gone...
to Mapleton.
现在我们以此为假设
Now let us use that as a working hypothesis.
这片土地十分干硬
The ground around here is very hard and dry
但是那边的低洼地
but over there in that hollow
在星期一的晚上肯定是很湿润
it must have been very wet on Monday night.
如果我们的假设是正确的
If our supposition is correct,
它肯定去过那里
he must have crossed it.
华生
Watson!
天 看看这个
By George, look at that.
你瞧见了想象力的可贵
You see the value of imagination
这正是Gregory督察缺少的一项资质
is the one quality,
which Inspector Gregory lacks.
我们想象可能发生的事情
We imagined what might have happened,
然后采取行动
acted upon the supposition,
最后发现是有道理的
and find ourselves justified.
让我们继续吧
Let us proceed.
看...看!
Look!
马和人...都折回了
Horse and man turned.
"Mapleton驯马场 闲人禁入"
这里不准闲人逗留
No loitering around here.
你没长眼睛吗
Haven't you got eyes in your head.
我只是想问你一个问题
I only wanted to ask you a question.
要是明天早晨五点我来拜访 Silas Brown先生 会不会太早了
Should I be too early
to see Mr. Silas Brown,
if I was to call around here
我不应该跟你说话
at five-thirty tomorrow morning?
I shouldn't be speaking to you by rights.
给 男孩
Here lad
please accept.
Bless you, sir.
You're a gentleman.
Brown先生是这里起最早的
Mr. Brown's the early bird
Dawson
around here all right.
你跟陌生人说三道四的干什么
Dawson?
What are you doing gossiping with strangers?
干你自己的事去
Be about your business.
你们两个在这里想干什么
Now what the devil do you two want around here?
只占用你一点时间 Brown先生
Just a few minutes of your time, Mr. Brown.
离开这里 不然你就会被狗追着跑
Be off with you
or you'll find the dog on your heels.
我为什么要和所有 在这旷野上游荡的陌生人说话?
Why should I talk every
gadabout stranger on the moor?
或许能让你免于被Blackwaters勋爵解雇
It may save you instant dismissal
from Lord Blackwaters' service
不会锒铛入狱
and the stiffest prison sentence.
留心周围
Keep guard.
星期二一大早
Early Tuesday morning,
你像平时一样巡视马场
you're about the yard as usual,
看见了一匹马在沼泽里
when you saw a horse on the moor.
等你靠近它时你意识到
When you approached it you realized
这完全不是一匹陌生的马
that it wasn't a strange horse at all.
是你熟知的一匹马 了如指掌
It was one that you knew, very well.
你的第一个反应就是带着银…
Your first instinct was to lead Silver...
银额马回到King's Pyland
Silver Blaze back to King's Pyland
但是随即你有了其他邪恶的想法
but then the devil put
other ideas into your head.
你有了赚一笔大钱的机会
You have a chance to make a great deal of money.
你突然反应过来 如果把马藏起来...
It occurred to you
that if you were to hide the horse...
你一直在看着我 对吧
You've been watching me haven't you?
你在监视我 先生
You've been spying on me, sir.
那么
Now.
瞧 先生
Sir.
你想让我做什么都行
I do what you want.
如果你要钱...
If it's money you want
会给你...
you shall have it.
我怎么说你就怎么做
You will do exactly as I tell you.
我很少见到像Silas Brown这样的 集霸道 怯懦和狡猾于一体的完美的组合
A more perfect compound
of the bully, coward and sneak
that Master Silas Brown
I've seldom met with.
那么说马在他那里?
He has the horse then?
当然
Of course.
但是他的马厩被搜过
But his stables have been searched.
像他这样的作假老手 知道很多伎俩
An old faker like him
knows many a dodge.
华生我不知道你是否注意到
Watson, I didn't know whether you observed
但是Ross上校地举止有点傲慢
but Colonel Ross' manner
has been somewhat cavalier.
我想要对他开点玩笑
I'm inclined to have a little amusement
at his expense.
不要向他透露任何马的事情
Say nothing to him about the horse.
没有你的允许 我什么都不会说
I shall say nothing without your permission.
非常好
Splendid.
从我们找到的线索来看
We have found traces,
星期一晚上在凶案现场一英里之外
which show that a party of gypsies
encamped on Monday night
吉普赛人在露营开过派对
within a mile of where the murder took place.
Fitzroy Simpson可能跟他们商量好了
Fitzroy Simpson
may well have an understanding with them
来把马藏起来
over hiding the horse.
尽管如此
Nevertheless,
让银额马退出比赛
I think I owe it to the public
让我依然觉得有愧于大家
to remove Silver Blaze's name
for the entrance for the cup.
不  当然不行
No, certainly not!
上校 我会让这个名字留下
Colonel, I should let the name stand.
但是我已经让Bayard退出了
But I've already withdrawn Bayard.
但是我有把握让银额马在星期六上场
But I have every hope
that Silver Blaze will start on Saturday.
让你的骑师做准备吧
Have your jockey at readiness.
我很高兴听到你的观点 先生
I'm very glad to have your opinion, sir.
当然跟谁杀了John Straker比 这只是个次要问题
That is a minor point, of course,
compared with the question
of who killed John Straker.
毫无疑问你会专注于这个问题
Doubtless you will be devoting yourself
正好相反 华生医生和我
to that problem.
On the contrary, Doctor Watson and I
会坐夜间特快回伦敦
were taking the Night Express to London.
我们已经呼吸过了你们这 诱人的新鲜空气
We've had the most charming little breath
of your country air.
所以你已经对缉拿杀害 John Strake的凶手丧失信心了
So you've despaired already of arresting
the murderer of poor John Straker.
困难重重
With our certain grave difficulties.
你有Straker的照片吗
Do you have the photograph of Straker?
谢谢 督察
Thank you, Inspector.
我已经准备好去Tavistock了
I am quite ready now for Tavistock.
留在这
Linger.
我必须说我对我们伦敦的顾问非常失望
I must say I am rather disappointed
in our London consultant.
我没有看到他来之后有任何的进展
I don't see that were any further than when he came.
但是至少他保证了你的马可以参赛 上校
But at least you have his assurance Colonel
that your horse will run.
哦 是的 他是保证了
Oh yes, I have his assurance.
但我宁愿得到马
I should prefer to have the horse.
我觉得你应该采纳 福尔摩斯先生的建议 上校
I think you should
heed Mr. Holmes advice, Colonel.
看情况再说吧
Well I shall have to see.
不好意思 是谁在照看这些羊?
Excuse me,
是我 先生
whom looks after these sheep?
I do, sir.
你有注意到它们最近有什么毛病吗
Have you noticed anything amiss of late?
没有 先生
No sir.
那也许算不上
Well it's not much account,
但是有三只羊的脚跛了
but three of them have gone lame.
谢谢
Thank you.
大胆的推测 华生 很大胆的推测 你先请
A long shot, Watson, a very long shot.
After you.
督察 我建议你注意下羊群中 这种奇异病症吧
Inspector I would like to recommend to you
the singular epidemic among the sheep.
你真的认为那很重要
You really consider that to be important?
非常重要
Exceedingly so.
走了 Baynes
All right Baynes.
你还需要我注意其它一些问题吗 福尔摩斯先生?
Is there any other point
to which you wish to draw my attention, Mr. Holmes?
那天夜里 狗的反应很奇怪
To the curious incident
of the dog in the nighttime.
但是那天夜里 狗没什么反应啊
But the dog did nothing in the nighttime.
那正是奇怪的地方
That is the curious incident.
我的马到底在哪里 福尔摩斯?
Where the devil is my horse, Holmes?
不 不 不 不 它到底在哪?
No, no, no, no,
我猜 上校
Where the devil is he?
如果你看见了 就可以认出它吧
I suppose, Colonel,
that you would recognize him
认出我自己的马?!
if you saw him?
我在赛马场上活跃了二十年了
Know my own horse?
I have been on the turf for twenty years
以前从来没有被这么问过 这样该死的傻问题
and I've never been asked
即使是一个孩子也知道
such a damn fool question before.
A child would know Silver Blaze
银额马的额头上有块白色的星型 后腿上有斑点
with the white star on his forehead
and mottled hind leg.
我想你能意识到如果我的马不上场
I suppose you realize if my horse doesn't run,
除了很可能会被人群报复
quite a part from being lynched by the crowd,
我还要去向赛马调查委员会自首
I shall be up before the Stewards'.
可能会被每个英格兰的赛马场永远禁赛
Probably warned off
声败名裂
every racecourse in England for life.
哦 希望不会发展到那个地步 上校
Reputation ruined.
Awe, let us hope it does not come to that, Colonel.
这是华生医生
Here's Doctor Watson.
而这匹 上校...
And this, Colonel,
就是你的马
is your horse.
那不是我的马 福尔摩斯
But that's not my horse, Holmes!
我的天啊 你都干了些什么
Good God man, what have you done?
上校啊 这就是你的银额马
There Colonel is your Silver Blaze.
我从盗马贼手里发现了它
I found him in the hands of a faker
原封不动带回了这里
and brought him to the course just as he was.
老天爷
Good heavens.
你太让我激动了 福尔摩斯先生
You take my breath away, Mr. Holmes.
银额马
Silver Blaze.
如果它还参赛的话
If he runs me lord
就会赢得名次吧 阁下
to win a place me lord?
当然会
To win, of course.
还有谁会像你吗?
Any more like you at home?
快跑 银额马 跑啊!
快点
Run Silver Blaze, run!
那匹该死的马到底是怎么回事啊
Come on!
What's the matter with the damn horse?
福尔摩斯 你对它做了什么
What have you done to him Holmes?
它失去了当领跑者的本领
He seems to be missing his pacemaker.
我不应该让Bayard退出
I should have never withdrawn Bayard.
等一下 他突破重围了
Wait a minute he's breaking through.
加油 银额马!
Come on Silver Blaze.
Silver Blaze!
快跑 快跑!
Go on.
你创造了奇迹 福尔摩斯先生
You've done wonders Mr. Holmes,
我欠你几千个道歉
and I owe you a thousand apologies
因为我怀疑了你的能力
for having doubted your ability.
你找回了我的马 出色得完成了工作
Now you've done me a great service
by recovering my horse.
如果你可以抓住杀害 John Straker的凶手的话就更好了
You'd do me a greater still
if you could lay your hands
我已经抓住了
on the murderer of John Straker.
I've done so.
什么?
What?
如果你已经得手 他现在人呢?
What's all this about if you got him.
他就在这里
Where is he then?
这里 哪里?
He's here.
此时...此地
Here!
Where?
Some who's now present at this very moment.
是的 我很清楚
Yes I quite recognize
自己欠你一份人情 福尔摩斯先生
that I'm under obligations to you Mr. Holmes,
但如果这不是一个非常烂的笑话 就是一种侮辱
but this either a very bad joke or an insult.
哦 上校 真正的杀人犯 就站在你的后面
Oh the real murderer, Colonel,
is standing immediately behind you.
什么 这匹马
What the horse?
是的 这匹马
Yes, the horse.
如果我说它完全是自卫才这么做 也许可以减轻它的罪过
And it may lessen his guilt if I say
that it was done entirely in self-defense,
而且John Straker这个人
and that John Straker
完全不值得你的信任
was a man quite unworthy of your trust.
四号 先生 第一名
Number four, sir, winner.
快来 Ross
Come Ross.
好的 非常感谢
Yes, thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
十二号
Number twelve.
我非常引以为豪
Very proud of it.
很骄傲
Very proud.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Thank you.
我承认 先生们
I confess, gentlemen,
当我们来King's Pylan的时候
when we came down to King's Pylan,
我曾经被说服了Fitzroy Simpson就是真凶
I was convinced that Fitzroy Simpson
所有的报纸和警方的报告 似乎都指向那一点
was the true culprit.
All the newspaper and police reports
seemed to point to it.
直到我进入驯马师房里
It was only when
I entered the trainer's house
想起了咖喱羊肉具有重要意义
that the immense significance
of the curried mutton occurred to me.
我要承认即使到现在
I confess that even now
我还不能明白它对我们有什么帮助
I cannot see how it helps us.
麻醉药 上校
Powdered opium, Colonel,
绝对不会完全无味
is by no means tasteless.
我说的对吗?
I am correct?
哦 完全正确
Oh quite correct.
味道不至于难吃
The flavor is not distasteful
但是它是可以尝出来的
but it is perceptible.
如果它混在一般的饭菜里
Were it mixed with an ordinary dish
吃的人一定会发觉
the eater would undoubtedly detect it
可能就不会继续吃了
but would probably eat no more.
咖喱恰好可以掩盖这股味道
Curry was exactly the medium
with which to disguise the taste.
所以那一定是Straker或者是他的妻子
So it must have been Straker or his wife?
没错
Exactly.
我想起来你提起过狗
Cause I remember you spoke of a dog.
是的 那只晚上没有吠叫的狗
Yes, the dog that didn't bark in the night.
有人走进了马厩
Well someone had been into the stable
并且牵走了马
and taken out the horse
狗却没有叫
and the dog had not barked.
所以很明显这个午夜访客 是狗很熟悉的人
So obviously this midnight visitor
was someone the dog knew well.
我本来就不相信会是陌生人
I wasn't really convinced that it was a stranger.
但是为了什么他要把马牵出去
But for what purpose
还给自己的马倌下药呢?
should he take out the horse
and drug his own stable boy?
显然他是个大骗子
A dishonest one, obviously.
之前就有过驯马师把赌注 下在自己马的败北上
There have been cases before now
where trainers have made great sums of money
by laying against their own horses
然后从中作梗而赚下一大笔
and then preventing them from winning.
有时候故意找个骑术不佳的骑师
Well sometimes you get a poorling jockey,
有时候就用更有把握 最狡诈的方式
I will say that.
And sometimes
by surer and most subtler means.
这把...
This
奇特的刀
singular knife,
是在死者的手上发现的
it was found in the dead man's hand
正常人不会用它当作武器 对吧?
and which no sane man
would use as a weapon, right?
哦 是的 只有...只有在 最精密的手术里才会使用
Oh yes, only, only used
它那天晚上
in the most delicate operations.
是用在了一个很精密的手术上
It was used for a
very delicate operation that night.
不好意思
Excuse me.
如你所知 上校
As you know, Colonel,
凭你丰富的赛马经验
with your wide knowledge of turf matters
在马的后踝骨腱子肉上 从皮下划一小道轻轻的伤口
that it is possible to make a slight nick
in the horse's tendon,
and do it, subcutaneously.
轻微的跛足会被认为是训练过度
Any slight lameness
will be put down to a strain in training
或是挫伤 不会被想到是一个肮脏的阴谋
or bruised, never foul play.
恶棍 该死的无赖
Villain!
The damn Scoundrel!
手术不能在马厩里进行
Not an operation to be done in the stable.
我不要吃的
No food for me.
马这么敏感的生物
So sensitive a creature
会吵醒熟睡的人
would arouse the soundest of sleepers.
我和Gregory都瞎了眼
I've been blind and Gregory too.
怪不得他需要蜡烛 还有划过的火柴
Of course, that's why he needed the candle
and struck the match.
当我检查随身物品时
When I examined Straker's belongings
我非常幸运地不仅发现了...
I was fortunate enough to discover
他的犯罪方法
not only the method of the crime
还有犯罪动机
but also the motive.
大部分人不会把别人的账单 放进自己的口袋里
Most men do not carry
other people's bills in their pockets.
从这点我总结出
From this I concluded
Straker是过着双重身份的生活
that Straker was leading a double life.
那账单的种类可以看出
The nature of the bill
这个案子里有一个女人
shows that there was a woman in the case.
而且是一个喜欢昂贵东西的女人
And a woman of expensive taste.
尽管你对你的仆人很大方
Liberal though you are with your servants,
我很确定他们也承受不起
I'm sure they're not able to afford
花二十二基尼为女人买件衣服
twenty-two guinea, walking dresses for their ladies.
照Straker夫人的说法 她从来没有这样的衣服
Mrs. Straker never had one by her own admission.
第二天早上我去邦德街
When I visited Bond Street the other morning,
把Straker的照片给Lesurier夫人时
I showed Madame Lesurier
this photograph of Straker.
她认出了他
She recognized him
他是一位很好的顾客  叫William Derbyshire
as an extremely good customer
called William Derbyshire,
有一位非常时髦的年轻妻子
with a very dashing young wife
她非常偏爱昂贵的裙子
with a partiality for expensive dresses.
女人 女人!
Women!
我想是她让他负债累累
I suppose it was she
陷入了这般窘境
who plunged him head over heels into debt
and so left him to his miserable plot?
Straker把银额马领到低洼地
Straker let out Silver Blaze into the hollow
在那里 他的烛光不会被马场的人看见
where his light would not be visible from the yard.
Simpson在逃跑中落下了围巾
Simpson in his flight
had dropped his scarf.
Straker捡起了它
Straker picked it up
毫无疑问 他是要用绑住马腿
with the idea, no doubt,
that he might use it
in securing the horses leg.
Straker把蜡烛点着了
Straker was able to light his candle
但是就在他准备动刀时
but just as he had the knife ready
马突然给他的额头来了致命一击
the horse lashed out
and caught him a fatal blow on the forehead.
为什么
Why?
为什么马会突然发起攻击呢?
And why did the horse lash out so suddenly?
是被蜡烛 还是刀吓着了?
Frightened by the candle, the knife?
动物有一种奇怪的本能
Well animals have a strange instinct.
它们似乎知道谁不怀好意
They seem to know
when some mischief is intended.
我必须承认 我最后的推测非常大胆
My final shot I must confess, was a long one.
我突然想到 像Straker这样精明的人
It struck me that such astute man,
在进行马腱手术之前一定做过练习
as Straker would not undertake this
tendon-nicking without a little practice.
那些羊
The sheep!
没错
Of course!
太精彩了 亲爱的
Wonderful, my dear.
现在你只剩下一件事没有解释
Now you've explained
all but one thing.
那匹马..马在哪里?
The horse.
Now where was the horse?
在这方面我们必须要宽容一点 上校
Well I think we must have
a little amnesty in that direction, Colonel.
它在外面被你其中一位邻居照顾着
It bolted and was looked after
by one of your neighbors.
先生们我现在为你们献上一段祝酒词
Gentlemen I give you a toast
献给银额马
to Silver Blaze
以我的朋友
coupled with the names of my friends,
夏洛克 福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Sherlock Holmes
和华生医生之名
and Doctor Watson.
敬银额马
To Silver Blaze.
风软FRM字幕组作品  -==http://www.1000fr.com==-  欢迎加入